不要
Ohh--no...
嘘
Shh.
真 爱 字 幕 组
出 品
翻译 校对：依依
翻译 校对：江米球
翻译：Livia
翻译：Ellen
翻译：Sophia
翻译：飞跃无限
翻译 监制：幸福ing形式
Edward ray stokes FBI
Edward ray stokes, fbi!
放下枪
Drop the gun!
你们先放下
You first.
我们收到了你的信 edward
We got your letters, edward.
读了每一个字
I read every single one of them.
那你明白了
Then you understand.
是 我明白你的愤怒
Yeah, I understand that you're angry...
你心灵受到创伤
And you hurt inside.
但那个女孩 她叫sheryl
But that girl, her name is sheryl
她不是你母亲
And she is not your mother.
她没有像你母亲一样伤害你
She didn't hurt you like your mother did.
她必须死
She needs to die.
不 不是今天
No. Not today.
放下枪 edward
Put it down, edward!
啊
Ah!
Blake 你还好吗
Blake. Are you all right?
还好
Yeah.
我们需要医生
We need a medic!
我没事  我还好  没事
I'm all right. I'm ok. I'm all right.
没问题 hotch 机场见
Uh-huh. You got it, hotch. We'll meet you at the airport.
嘿
Hey.
你确定没事
You sure you're ok?
没事 没有什么
Oh, yeah. It's nothing.
离要害就几英寸
A couple inches to your right
他本可以射击你的臂动脉
and he could have hit your brachial artery.
总之 你相当幸运啊
All things considered, you were extraordinarily lucky.
与运气无关
Yeah, luck had nothing to do with it.
实际上我刀枪不入
I'm practically bulletproof.
我听说过
Yeah, I heard that about you.
好吧  快点完事回家吧
All right, let's finish this up and go home.
老爸
Hey, dad.
我很好
Yeah, I'm good.
你还好吗
How are you doing?
不 不 我们才完事
No, no, we're just finishing up here.
不 我们其实在
No, we're actually,
阳光充足的洛杉矶
Uh, in sunny los angeles.
为什么 一切还好吗
Why? Everything ok?
帮什么忙
Help with what?
好的 长官 我准备好了
Ok, sir, I'm ready.
好的 大家注意一下
All right. Can I have your attention, everyone.
说吧 garcia
Go ahead, garcia.
那好 昨晚在堪萨斯城
Alrighty, then. Last night in kansas city--
严格地说是今天清晨
Well, technically super early this morning--
50岁的david morrison
50-year-old david morrison
慢跑时被打死了
was beaten to death when he was out jogging.
信息显示在你们的平板上
Information is on your tablets right now.
真残忍
It looks brutal.
典型的暴力杀害
Classic overkill.
他被剥光  穿着女人的内衣
He was found stripped and wearing women's underwear
我想内衣应该不是他的
That I'm assuming weren't his.
没错 附近发现了他所有的衣物
Yeah. All of his clothes were found nearby,
包括内衣
his skivvies included.
有性侵犯的迹象吗
Any evidence of sexual assault?
我们还在等报告结果
We're still waiting on the m.E. Report.
有其他受害者吗 garcia
Any other victims, garcia?
大有可能
That is a big maybe.
看看tommy barnes和melissa hawthorne
Meet tommy barnes and melissa hawthorne,
也显示在你们的平板上
Also on your tablets.
一年前 他们在家庭派对上消失
A year ago they disappeared from a house party
然后被发现以相同的手法暴打致死
And were found beaten in much the same fashion.
这两个人 他们明显
There were two of them and they're considerably younger
比最近的受害者年轻
Than this most recent victim.
女人的内衣呢
Yeah, and what about the women's underwear?
就像是一种特定仪式
And that's a pretty specific ritual aspect.
这两个都穿着衣服
These two were found fully clothed.
确定是同一嫌犯所为吗
Are we sure that it's the same unsub?
我老爸这样认为
My dad thinks it is.
你爸是堪萨斯城的城市警察 对吧
Your dad's a captain on the kansas city police force, right?
退休了
Retired.
但你哥哥也是警察
But your brother's a cop, too.
Scott 他是罪案侦探
Scott. He's a homicide detective,
但打电话的是我爸
But my dad is the one who made the call.
如果他退休了 这未必就是官方邀请
If he's retired, it's not exactly an official invitation.
但他很有影响力
No, but he's got lots of influence.
也许我们应该等候邀请
Well, maybe we should wait for the invite.
我们不能强行介入当地管辖范围
We can't just force ourselves on local jurisdiction.
如果是连杀案呢
What if it's actually serial?
如果他们要求 我们就回去
We'll go back if they ask us to.
听着 我爸是一个伟大的警察 他几乎没犯过错
Look, my dad's a great cop, and he's almost never wrong.
我是说 我快疯了 但那是真的
I mean, it drives me crazy, but it's true.
我们不确定到底得到了什么线索
We don't know exactly what we've got here,
但我认为值得看一下
But I think it's worth taking a look.
让飞行员返航去堪萨斯城
Have the pilot reroute us to kansas city.
兄弟姐妹亲如手足
"Brothers and sisters are as close as hands and feet."
越南谚语
Vietnamese proverb.
David morrison是一名小说家
David morrison was a novelist,
Tommy barnes和melissa hawthorne是高中生
Tommy barnes and melissa hawthorne high school students.
受害人之间没有明显联系
No apparent connection between the victims,
DNA采样不匹配
No matching dna samples.
被害相隔整整一年
And an entire year between kills.
内衣仪式或许是关于象征性的羞辱
You know, the underwear ritual may be about symbolic humiliation.
或者是给发现者的冲击
Or a shock factor for whoever found the bodies.
Blake 你爸爸有提到其他的原因吗
Blake, did your dad say anything
为什么他认为这些案件是有关联的
else about why he thinks these cases are connected?
Blake
Yeah? Blake?
还好吗
Everything all right?
没事 抱歉
Uh, yeah. Sorry.
只是有点分心
Just--I'm distracted.
可以理解 熟悉的声音 场景
Perfectly understandable. The familiar sounds, visual cues,
甚至味道 会触发记忆与情感
Even olfactory inputs, can trigger memories and emotions
那些以为离我们远去的东西
We thought were long gone.
每次我回家也这样
Happens to me every time I go home, too.
上次回家是什么时候
When was the last time you were back?
422天前
It's been like 422 days.
我在问blake
I was talking to blake.
差不多5年了
Uh, it's been about 5 years.
很久了
That's a long time.
是啊 一走出堪萨斯城
Yeah, once I got out of kansas city,
我就很想呆在外面
I pretty much wanted to stay out.
她最大的哥哥持械抢劫
Her oldest brother was responding to an armed robbery.
显然坏家伙都喜欢毒品
Apparently the bad guys were on pcp.
他和他的伙伴中枪 他最严重
Both he and his partner got shot and he got the worst of it.
我们怎么对此一无所知
How come we don't know any of this?
她该说什么
What's she supposed to say?
我不知道
I don't know.
随便说点什么
Something.
blake是个安静的人
Well, blake's a private person.
也许她不想和她的家人交流
Maybe she doesn't want to talk about her family.
而且已经过去25年 过去很久了
Plus it was over 25 years ago. A lot of time has passed.
我也是这样失去我父亲的
I lost my father the same way.
并不是我不想联系
It's not like I can't relate.
但你很少谈论他
Yeah, but you rarely talk about him.
每个人都有自己的悲伤
Everybody grieves in their own way.
你不能对她发怒
You can't be mad at her for going internal.
我才没有 我只是
Oh, I'm not mad at all. I just...
觉得她该说点什么
Thought she might say something.
这件事上 你帮不了忙
There's nothing for you to do here.
老爸预感此事时 你就应该知道
When dad has a hunch, you know how he gets.
没错 他直接打电话给garrity队长
Yeah, he called captain garrity directly.
然后呢
So, now what?
队长希望我配合 就这样
Well, the captain wants me to cooperate, that's what.
但你是在浪费时间
But you're wasting your time.
老爸似乎不这样看
Dad doesn't seem to think so.
那些孩子和morrison谋杀无关 好吗
Look, those kids had nothing to do with the morrison murder, ok?
他们被杀害在prospect被杀害
They were killed down on prospect
因为他们不过也就抓了一些小人物
Because they were out trying to cop some weed.
Prospect
Prospect?
Prospect大道 一个犯罪高发区
Uh, prospect avenue. It's a high crime area.
就是我们这个地方
It's the hood.
miller警探 我向你保证
Detective miller, I assure you
我们不是到这里侵权的
We're not here to intrude.
而且我确信在未来的24小时也不会
And I feel certain that in 24 hours
我们可以调查出这些案件是否相关
We'll be able to discern whether these cases are related.
我们真的做的很好 Scoot
We're really good at what we do, scott.
这是当然
Of course you are.
Alex?
这里
There.
爸爸
Dad.
哦...已经这么久了
Oh...been so long.
你看起来不错 抱歉我有点迟到
You look good. I'm sorry I'm a little late.
刚才在garrity的办公室耽搁了一会
I was down in garrity's office.
你一定是hotchner
You must be hotchner.
Damon miller 是的 先生
Damon miller. Yes, sir.
很高兴见到你
Very nice to meet you.
谢谢你能来
Appreciate you coming,
谢谢这么照顾我女儿
And thanks for taking such good care of my girl.
关于案子有什么计划?
So what's the plan of attack?
这里很偏僻
This place is pretty isolated.
使用棍子很方便
It helps to be out in the sticks
如果你要打死一个人
If you're going to beat someone to death.
听起来你很有经验
You sound like you speak from experience.
恩
Hmm.
David morrison是个50岁的小说家
David morrison was a 50-year-old novelist
显然还是个多才多艺的三项全能运动员
And apparently an accomplished triathlete.
埋伏的好地方
Good place for an ambush.
为什么要选这样一个人
But why pick the in-shape guy?
Morrison也许就是目标
Morrison could have been a target.
也许他认识凶手
Maybe he knew his killer.
他们可能有什么过节
But they may have had some kind of a beef.
打死一个人是个人行为
Beating someone to death is personal.
一定是有很强的愤怒
It takes a lot of anger.
这个人一定是身体很强健
Well, the unsub's got to be physically fit himself.
对 还有很高等级的暴力倾向
Yeah, he would have to be to maintain that level of violence.
他也有可能是个瘾君子
He could also be on drugs.
不错的假设
That's a good bet.
看起来像是毁灭性的攻击
All right, so, it looks like it's a blitz attack.
你觉得他怎么做到的
How do you think he did it?
凶手跟踪morrison
Well, the unsub stalks morrison
调查他的生活
And figures out that this is
知道他在哪晨跑
Where he takes his morning run.
然后他等待 藏起来
Then he waits, hides,
冲向他
Jumps him.
或者他跟踪他来这
Or he follows him out here,
把他制服 虽然morrison是三项全能
Runs him down, even though morrison is a triathlete.
我只希望这凶手没有别的目标了
Well, I just hope this guy doesn't have any more targets.
如果这是愤怒或者是成瘾了
If this is rage and addiction...
那他还没完
He's not done.
我只是说
I'm just saying,
你可以打给我的 爸爸
You could have called me, dad.
直接去找我上司
Going straight to my boss?
还有她
Oh, and her.
你觉得这会让我看起来怎样?
I mean, how do you think this makes me look?
因为什么 因为你的直觉
Because why? Because you have a hunch?
那如果我打电话你会说什么?
And what would you have said if I'd called?
我会...
I'd...
恩-恩
Uh-huh.
就是这样
Exactly.
她不像是伸手要什么
And it's not like she would ever reach out and offer.
她已经有五年没有在家了
She hasn't been home in 5 years.
我应该飞去washington看她
I had to fly out to washington just to see her.
我就在这
I'm right here, you know.
听着 我只是想说
Look, all I'm saying, dad,
这个部门其实
Is the last thing this
无非需要的只是这样一个消息
department needs is some bad press that comes
就是FBI到这来抓连环杀手
From an fbi serial killer hunt.
不是
No.
这个部门最需要的
The last thing this department needs
是将这个连环杀手伏法
Is a serial killer on the loose.
她说得没错
She's right.
而且你也知道
And you know it.
你知道么 爸爸
You know what, dad?
什么
What?
什么 来啊 来啊 说出来
What?! Come on, come on, speak up.
你退休了
Hey. You're retired.
他 他退休了
He's--he's retired.
好么 为什么你还一直坚持
Ok? And why are you sticking your nose
一件和你无关的事情
Where it doesn't belong?
因为我是你爸
Because I am your father
我想坚持我就坚持
And I will stick my nose wherever I damn well please
除非我死了 而且就我的年纪来看
Until the day I die, and given my age,
那一天也不远了
That day ain't too far off.
怎么 我老了 爸
What? I'm old. Dad...
但是我跟你做个交易
But I'll make you a deal.
现在开始你们得表现的亲密一点
You two both start acting like you're related
我走了
And I'll butt out.
抓到这个凶手的唯一方法
The only way you're gonna catch this guy
就是你们团结起来
Is if you do it together.
没 只是点咖啡因
No, just a little caffeine.
还有 他的兴奋剂检测结果是阴性
Other than that, his tox screen was negative.
他脖子周围有非常重的淤青
That pretty heavy bruising around his neck.
死因是窒息
Yeah. Cause of death was asphyxiation.
看到这里奇怪的颈椎骨折了么?
And you see this odd little cervical fracture right here?
看起来他是被什么闷住的
It looks like he got put in some kind of choke hold.
闷死一个人是很困难的
Choking someone out is hard enough,
但是在做这事的时候弄断他们的脖子
But to break their neck while you do it?
好吧 他是个该死的壮汉
Yeah, well, he was a strong son of a bitch.
四根肋骨断了 左臂粉碎
4 ribs were broken, radius in his left arm was shattered,
颅骨线形骨折 下巴破裂
Linear fracture in his skull, broken jaw,
脾脏破裂
And a ruptured spleen.
能告诉我他可能用了什么武器么
Can you tell if he used a weapon?
我认为他没用什么武器 看到这的淤青了么
I don't think he did. See this bruising right here?
看来他就是用他的手而已
It looks like he used his bare hands,
也许是他的靴子
Maybe his boots.
但是他被闷死的相当迅速
But he was suffocated fairly quickly.
大部分这些都是死后造成的
Most of this is postmortem.
这家伙一定在经历什么
This guy had to be on something.
为什么这么说?
Why do you say that?
因为他疯了
Because he went berserk.
这不仅仅是愤怒了
This is more than just rage.
有性侵犯的迹象吗
Was there any evidence of sexual assault?
没有
None.
这和tommy barnes或者melissa hawthorne看起来都不一样
It wasn't like this with tommy barnes or melissa hawthorne.
那两个被杀的高中生
Those two high school kids who were killed.
报告里说他们没有任何死后造成的伤痕
The report says that they didn't have any postmortem wounds.
你觉得这是同一个凶手?
God, you think it's the same guy?
我们还得这样来一次么
Do we have to go through this again?
不是都写到报告里了么
Isn't it all in your report?
非常抱歉 Barnes先生
I apologize, mr. Barnes.
我知道这是很难的
I know this is hard.
我们想更彻底一点
We're just trying to be thorough
那样我们才能抓到杀害你儿子的凶手
So we can catch whoever did this to your son.
我的回答和一年前他们问我的都是一样的
All my answers are the same they were a year ago.
但是因为是你发现tommy 和 melissa的
But since you were the one that actually found tommy and melissa,
这点尤其重要
It's especially important
所以我们还要再来一遍
That we go through it all again.
好吗
Ok?
现在跟我讲讲那个晚上
You were telling me about that night.
已经很晚了 你开始担心了
It was late and you were getting worried.
然后我记得tommy
And then I remembered that tommy
在我手机里加了一个"找朋友"的软件
Put that "Find your friends" App on my phone.
所以
So...
几个小时以后
And a couple hours later
我在山谷中发现了他和Melissa
I found him and melissa in the alley.
Tommy有死敌吗
Did tommy have any enemies,
可能会伤害他的人
Someone that might want to hurt him?
不  他是个好孩子  我已经说过了
No, he was a good kid. I said that already.
好吧  听着
All right, listen. We
感谢你能过来   Barnes先生
want to thank you for coming in, mr. Barnes.
非常感谢
We appreciate it. If we have
如果其他问题   我们再给你打电话
any other questions, we'll give you a call.
事实上  你能在等会吗
Actually...will you give us a second?
我还有几个问题  不会太久的
I just have a few more questions. Won't take long.
Scott
Scott.
抱歉
Excuse us.
他在竭力隐瞒什么东西
He's holding something back.
他只是为失去儿子而悲伤
He's grieving the loss of his son.
没错  从他坐下的那一刻
Exactly. And he's been trying to get out of here
他就一直想离开这里
Ever since he sat down.
你能怪他吗
Can you blame him?
如果我自己的孩子被杀害了
If I had a kid who was killed
FBI想帮我找出凶手的话
And the fbi wanted to help find the guy who did it,
我愿意配合他们做任何事
I would do whatever they asked me to.
看看他的神态
Look at his posture.
焦躁不安
He's too agitated.
他说的话很可疑  我不能
There is something odd about his syntax I can't...
我也说不上来是什么
That I can't explain.
为什么呢   因为这个案件对我来说太复杂了吗
And why is that? Because that profile's too complicated for me?
是这样吗
Really?
真是这样吗
现在吗
Right now?
拜托  Scott
Please, scott,
就这一次
For once,
按我说的办吧
Just go with me here.
Barnes先生  很抱歉要问你这个问题
Mr. Barnes, I am so sorry to have to ask you this,
但我不想浪费你的时间
But I don't want to waste your time.
我做的一切都是为了抓住凶手
All I want to do is catch the killer,
但没有你的配合  我是抓不到的
But I can't do that unless you're straight with me.
Alex
Alex.
当你找到Tommy和Melissa的时候
When you found tommy and melissa,
他们穿衣服了没
Were they clothed?
我不知道你什么意思
I don't know what you mean.
我是说  Tommy是不是穿着女孩的内衣呢
I mean, was tommy in girls underwear?
如果你想要尊重你儿子的回忆
If you want to honor your son's memory,
或者给其他受害者的亲人一点安慰
Maybe bring some peace to the relatives of the other victims...
那就拜托了
Then, please,
拜托告诉我真相吧
Just tell me the truth.
我不能  不能
I couldn't--I couldn't...
不  没事的  我们是要帮你
No, it's all right. We only want to help.
当我找到他们时
When I found them...
她没穿衣服  而Tom
She was naked, and tom...
Tommy穿着女孩的内裤
Tommy, he was in girls panties,
我只是
And I just...
不能让他们看见他穿成这样  所以
Couldn't let them see him like that, so...
我就给他脱了下来
I took them off and...
穿在了Melissa的身上  我
I put them on melissa and I...
我给他们都把衣服穿好了  抱歉
I put all their clothes back on. I'm so sorry.
不  没事的
No, it's all right.
准备好了吗
We ready?
就等你了  亲爱的
Just waiting on you, hon.
什么东西
What was that?
你把Rufus放出去了吗
Did you let rufus out?
我以为是你放出去的
I thought you did.
噢
Tsk. Oh...
Rufus
Rufus?
Oh, rufus.
没事吧
Everything ok?
没事  是这只笨猫
Yeah. This dumb cat.
嘿
Hey!
Gil和Renee Patterson都是勤劳善良的人
Gil and renee patterson were good, hard-working people.
他是银行经理  而她是个护士
He was a bank manager, she was a nurse.
如果目标是这些受害者的话  这其中有什么关联呢
If all these victims were targets, then what's the connection?
也许目标不在他们  他们只是替罪羊
Maybe they're not targets. Maybe they're surrogates.
替谁呢
For who?
很明显  一个邻居在路过时看到门虚掩着
So, um, apparently, a neighbor found the bodies
然后发现了尸体
When she came by and saw the door was ajar.
Patterson夫妇有近亲吗
Do the pattersons have any next of kin?
我们需要和他们谈谈
We're gonna need to talk to them.
没错  有一个女儿叫做laurie
Yeah, they do. They have a daughter named laurie.
是密苏里州大学的大四学生
She's a senior at the university of missouri.
惯用手法
M.O.'s THE EXACT SAME.
女人的内衣  人为的过度暴力伤害
Women's underwear, violent manual overkill.
显然是同一个人
It's definitely our guy.
他现在变本加厉了
And now he's accelerating.
胆子也越来越大了
And he's getting bolder.
他之前从未入过室
He's never broken into a home before.
你发现什么了
Hey, what you got, mama?
实际上死去的David Morrison
So it turns out our dead jogger david morrison
在出版第一本书之前
Bounced around as a substitute english teacher
曾是名代课老师
Before he published his first book.
四年前  他曾在Jefferson高中工作过一个星期
4 years ago, he worked for a week at jefferson high school,
那所学校正是
And that is the same school
Tommy Barnes和Melissa Hawthorne曾上学的地方
That tommy barnes and melissa hawthorne went to.
Patterson夫妇有个女儿  Laurie
Laurie. Jj: the pattersons have a daughter.
Garcia  Laurie Patterson上哪个高中
Garcia, where did laurie patterson go to high school?
是在  Jefferson
That would be...jefferson.
她是什么时候毕业的
And when did she graduate?
嗯
Um...
四年前
4 years ago.
所以说她和Morrison同时在那上学
So she was there at the same time morrison was.
好的  我会给Hotch打电话  我们需要发文件
All right, I'll call hotch. We need to give the profile.
基于受害者和当地人口统计
Based on his victims and on local demographics,
可以认定我们在找的是个毕加索男子
We believe we're looking for a caucasian male
在他十几岁到二十几岁的时候
IN HIS LATE TEENS TO EARLY 20s.
他是个虐待狂 有暴力倾向
He's a sadist with rage issues,
那就解释了
Which accounts for the
他杀害的五个受害者都是
All 5 of his victims are in
和Jefferson高中有关的
some way connected to jefferson high school.
这使我们有理由相信
Which leads us to believe
他要么曾是那的学生  要么是前雇员
he's either a former student or employee.
为什么是之前的
Why former?
因为我们还认为他有染毒品
Because we also think he has a drug problem.
毒瘾加上暴力问题
The addiction plus his anger issues
说明他可能缺少社会技能
Means that he probably lacks the social skills
需要呆在学校  或者有一份稳定的工作
Required to stay in school or hold down a steady job.
因为暴力和虐待
Because brute force and humiliation
是他惯用手法的特点
Are the hallmarks of his m.O.,
我们认为他杀人是为了报复
We believe his kills are somehow rooted in revenge.
他可能被虐待羞辱受过伤害
We think he may have been traumatically humiliated
可能在不久的过去
In some way in the recent past.
也许是青少年时候
Probably as an adolescent,
这是他心中隐私的部分
Which makes this very personal to him.
那他为什么在第一次犯罪后隔了一整年呢
So why did this guy wait a whole year after his first murders?
我们认为他可能被监禁过
We think he may have been incarcerated.
所以你应该看看暴力罪犯
So you should be looking at violent offenders
或者所有年轻点的你所熟悉的前科犯
Or any younger ex-cons you may be familiar with.
我们认为他的第一次谋杀是在做实验
We think his first kills were experiments of sorts.
他只是尝尝鲜
He was just getting a taste for it.
Tommy Barnes和melissa Hawthorne
Tommy barnes and melissa hawthorne
比其他的受害者受到的伤害都深
Had more defensive wounds than any of his other victims.
显然他们还做了好一番反抗
And they apparently put up quite a fight.
同时袭击两个人可不是件易事
It's not easy to blitz attack two people at once.
所以不论他是否被监禁了  他肯定用
So whether he was locked up or not, he probably took
一年来完善自己
A year off to perfect his
确保不再有意外发生
craft to make sure that never happened again.
他体型健康  也许经常锻炼
He's physically fit and probably works out a lot,
所以他有可能常去不贵的体育馆或者健康俱乐部
So he may frequent inexpensive gyms or heath clubs.
别忘了  这家伙徒手
And don't forget, this guy used his bare hands
杀死了受害者
To kill his victims.
他不会善罢甘休的
He will not be easily deterred.
所以我们要谨慎行事
So proceed with caution.
随着他越来越脱离现实
As his grip on reality continues to fade,
他会变得更危险
He'll become more dangerous.
收拾好你的东西  我们就要关门了
Hey, wrap it up, kid. We're closing.
等一下  再来两轮
Few more minutes. Two more rounds.
快滚出去  我要关门走了
Hey, get the hell out. I gotta get going.
啊
Ah!
我只要几分钟
I just need a few more minutes!
好吗
Ok?
你听清楚了没有
All right by you?
非常好 没问题
It's all good, man. No problem.
我可不想惹麻烦
I don't want any trouble.
我们应该反复核对一下
We should cross-check our
我们最近释放的前科犯的名单
list of recently released ex-cons again.
Garcia和我检查过两遍
Garcia and I have been over it twice.
没有和资料相符合的人
Nobody matches the profile.
小妞  你难住我们整个团队了 说吧
Hey, baby girl, you got the whole crew. Go ahead.
好吧  这是一个Jefferson高中的瘦小伙
Ok, here's the skinny on jefferson high.
是个好球队  一连两次夺冠
Really great football team, state champ two years in a row,
加油  伙计们
Go, bulldogs.
唯一值得注意的是那所高中
The only notable thing that has happened at that high school
在过去的10年中，除了
In the last 10 years besides the murder
Tommy Barnes 和Melissa Hawthorne的谋杀案
Of tommy barnes and melissa hawthorne
还有一个学生也遇害了
Is the death of another student,
Riley wilson，死于4年前
Riley wilson, 4 years ago.
发送中
Sending.
已将信息发至你的平板电脑
Information streaming to your tablets now.
他在一根电线杆旁边把他的车裹起来
He wrapped his car around a telephone pole.
很多人猜测这是一起自杀事件
Yeah. There was a lot of speculation it was a suicide.
报告里没有检出三聚甲醛
Tox report was clean.
他是完全清醒的
He was totally sober.
他是个高中生而且学习成绩一直优异
HE WAS A SENIOR AND GOT STRAIGHT As.
也没有处分记录
Nothing in his disciplinary file.
他在Jefferson读高中时
He was at jefferson the same
David Morrison和Laurie Patterson也在同所学校
time as david morrison and laurie patterson.
Garcia  我们需要Riley Wilson上学时
Garcia, we need a list of every student and employee
Jefferson高中所有学生和员工的名单
At jefferson while riley wilson was a student.
包括父母和家庭成员
Parents and family members, too, garcia.
列表正在筛选形成中
Compiling that list now.
名字太多了  我会尽快给你回电。
It is a lot of names. I will hit you back asap.
这是以前的学生的部分名单
Here's a partial list of former students
里面是仍然住在城里的人
Who still live in the city.
为什么只有部分名单
Why partial?
我们已经将范围缩小以便分工合作
We've narrowed it down so we can split the work.
我们会负责剩下的
We'll cover the rest.
好  我们继续努力吧
Ok. We'll get on it.
还有其中一个人可能是不明嫌犯
And, uh, one of those people may be the unsub,
那让你们那边的人注意一下
So, make sure your guys know.
明白了吗
You got it.
好
Ok.
你知道吗
Uh, you know...
如果不是听我爸爸的
I never would have shown up like I did
我压根就不该出现的
If dad hadn't asked me to.
我的意思是  我理解你
I mean, I get it.
你有权沮丧
You have every right to be upset.
Alex  没关系  好吧
It's all good, alex. Ok?
我好多年没见你了
Come on. I haven't seen you in years
现在我们有这机会共事了
And now we get this great chance to work together.
我得开始工作去了
I better get started.
Charles Gates
Charles gates?
是的
Yeah.
我是Milller探员
Detective miller.
堪萨斯州警局
Kansas city police department.
我能否问你几个问题呢
I was wondering if I could ask you a few questions.
当然
Um...sure.
我能进来吗
May I come in?
当然
Yeah, of course.
不好意思  有点乱   没关系
Um, sorry about the mess. No problem.
Laurie  我们你父母的事感到遗憾
Laurie, we're so very sorry about your parents.
谢谢你能来
Thank you for coming in.
谁知道会发生这种事  难以承受
We know this-- this is a lot.
没事  我
It's ok, I, uh,
现在还真不想回家
Don't really want to go home yet.
我们能帮你做点什么
Is there anything we can get you?
那我们现在问你几个问题可以吗
Is it ok if we ask you a few questions?
你能想到有谁
Is there anyone you know
可能伤害你父母的人吗
who may have wanted to hurt your parents?
不知道
No.
那有没有人可能会伤害你
Is there anyone who may have wanted to hurt you?
不知道 我
No, I--
天呐
Oh, my god.
对不起
I'm--I'm so sorry.
没关系
It's ok.
你自己待会  好吗
We're gonna give you a minute. Ok?
谢谢
Thank you.
当我听说他死了的时候我真不敢相信
I couldn't believe it when I heard he was dead.
我是说  Riley连酒都不喝
I mean, riley didn't even drink.
而且我前不久还见他呢
And I'd just seen him at school.
那么你和他关系很好是吧
So you two were pretty close.
是的
Yeah.
他不怎么喜欢社交
I mean, he wasn't all that social.
经常一个人独自呆着
He kept to himself a lot.
那么他是那种独来独往的人
So he was kind of a loner.
是的
Yeah.
但是我们经常翘课出去  我们很少一起上课
But we hung out. We had a few classes together.
骗子
Liar!
爸爸
Dad!
他还好吧 发生什么事情了
Is he ok? What happened?
他被打得挺严重的  特别是头部
He got beat up pretty bad. Took a blow to the head.
他有搭档吗  他的伙伴在哪里
Did he have backup? Where's his partner?
他一个人来的  为了混淆视听  他们是分头行动的
He came alone. They split up the list to cover more ground.
我们把他送到医院去
Let's get him to the hospital.
好  我跟你一起去
All right, I'm coming with you.
不用 你留在这 有更重要的事让你做
No, you stay here. You'll do more good.
别担心 我会照顾好他的
Don't worry. I'll-- I'll take care of him.
疑犯可能在你弟弟来之前就到了这里
The unsub was probably already here when your brother arrived.
但没杀他
But he didn't kill him.
因为Charles才是他的目标
Because charles was the target.
所以他弟弟只是诱饵
So this guy's mission oriented.
我认为疑犯可能已经偷了scott的枪支。
I believe the unsub may have stolen scott's firearm.
不符合他的作案手法  但不代表他不用
Doesn't match his m.O., but that won't stop him from using it.
这里有新发现
There's something in here.
他写道  Charles 和Riley是好朋友
He wrote, "Charles and riley good friends,"
但是在“好”和“朋友”下面划线强调了
But he underlined the words "Good" And "Friends."
对你来说有何意义
That mean something to you?
他小时候经常这么做
Yeah. He used to do that when we were kids.
通常被激怒了他才会这么做
Usually when something really irritated him.
他在字下面划线是因为他愤怒了吗
He underlined words when he was irritated?
没错  我母亲以前经常让我们互相写信
Yeah. Our mother used to make us write letters
来帮助我们解决我们的冲突
To each other to help us resolve our conflicts.
她认为这是一种学习
She thought it was a good way to learn
表达我们的感受的方式
How to express our feelings.
聪明的女士
Smart lady.
那好朋友的意思对他来说到底是关于什么呢
What was it about the words "Good friends" That got to him?
爸爸  他怎么样
Hey, dad, how's he doing?
嘿  laurie
Hi, laurie.
你好吗
How are you doing?
恐怕我还有些坏消息要告诉你
I'm afraid I have some more bad news.
凶手又行凶了
The killer struck again.
这次是你以前的同学
This time it was a former classmate of yours--
Charles Gates
Charles gates.
我知道这对你来说是令人难以置信的痛苦
I understand this is incredibly overwhelming,
但我们需要你的帮助
But we really need your help.
好吗  我想问你一些事
Ok? I want to ask you about charles
关于Charles和你老同学Riley Wilson
And another former classmate of yours, riley wilson.
有关他们的什么
What about them?
他们是好朋友么
Were they good friends?
Charles和Riley么  不是
Charles and riley? No.
Riley实际上没什么朋友
Riley didn't really have any friends.
为什么没有
Why not?
他是个纯种书呆子
He was a gigantic nerd
也是个彻头彻尾的受害者
And a total victim.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
他们过去经常欺负他
They used to bully him,
貌似一直那样
Like all the time.
他们都对他做过什么
What would they do to him?
取笑他  揍他
Tease him. Beat him up.
而且  而且还有件内衣事件
And then-- and then there was the underwear thing.
什么内衣事件
What underwear thing?
有人觉得如果体育课上
Some guys thought it'd be funny
偷走Riley的衣服会很有意思
If they stole all riley's clothes in gym class.
嘿  他出来了
Hey, here he is.
他们让他穿着一条女士短裤
They made him wear a pair of panties.
并且给学校里的每个人发短信
And then they sent out a mass text
告诉他们在走廊里站成一排
To everyone in school telling them to line the hallways.
基本上全学校的学生都到了
Basically the whole school showed up.
这个恶作剧是谁的主意
Whose idea was it to pull the prank?
我的前男友  Lance Tate
My ex-boyfriend, lance tate.
他是个混蛋
He was a jerk.
教师们当时在哪
Where were the teachers?
Ramsey先生和几个代课老师结束了这场闹剧
Mr. Ramsey and some substitute broke it up.
各回各班吧
Go back to class.
都回去
Everybody back to class!
表演结束了
Show's over.
他后来有没有出事
Did anything happen to him?
Lance惹上麻烦了么
Did lance get in trouble?
没有
No.
还有其他被欺负的孩子么
Were there any other kids
还是说Riley是唯一的一个
that were bullied or was riley the only one?
没错  还有其他人
Yeah, there were others.
你记得他们的名字么
Do you remember their names?
等下  那个  那个和这有关么
Wait. Is that-- is that what this is about?
那就是为什么我父母被杀的原因吗
Is that why my parents were killed?
天啊
Oh, my god.
Laurie Patterson那时不在学校
Laurie patterson was away at school,
所以他就不能跟踪她了
So he couldn't go after her.
所以他转而跟踪了他的父母
So he goes after her parents instead.
那就是他使她的痛苦最大化的方法
That was his way of maximizing her suffering.
Laurie的前男友  Lance Tate中士
Laurie's ex, sergeant lance tate,
第三次去阿富汗服役
Is doing his third tour in afghanistan.
他的父母移居到了亚利桑那州
His parents moved to arizona.
嘿  在听你说话  Garcia
Hey. You're on speaker, garcia.
刚刚出炉的  我拿到了Laurie给我们的名单
Hot off my keyboard, I took the names laurie gave us
我把它们和Riley Wilson的短信
And I cross-checked them with riley wilson's texts,
电子邮件以及社交媒体交叉比对了  得到了2个匹配记录
Emails, and social media. I got two hits.
一个是Kevin Russ  他的化学实验搭档
One's a kevin russ. That was his chemistry lab partner.
第二个也是更有意思的
And the second and the way more interesting
是一个叫做Ronald Underwood的孩子
Is a kid named ronald underwood.
他有什么有趣的
What's so interesting about him?
貌似他们是很好的朋友
It looks like they were actually pretty good friends.
Ronald刚好是在Riley死后辍学的
Ronald dropped of school right after riley died.
关于Underwood我们还知道什么
What else do we know about underwood?
父亲不在  他和母亲一起生活
Uh, dad is out of the picture. He lives with his mom,
她有四次酒后驾车记录
WHO HAS 4, 4 DUIs.
他在因特网上花费了难以想象的大把时间
He spends a cra-cra-crazy amount of time on the internet,
大部分是花在了浏览色情和综合搏击网站以及
Mostly looking at porn and mma sites and--
因特网也是他买到类固醇药物的地方
Oh. The internet is also where he buys his anabolic steroids.
如果这就是关于恃强凌弱的所有信息
If this is all about bullying,
那么嫌疑犯本人可能也会成为受害人
the unsub may have been a victim himself.
他也可能感到对Riley的死负有责任
He may also feel responsible for what happened to riley.
所以他将恃强者和没阻止Riley这场悲剧的
And he's targeting the bullies
家长作为了报复目标
and the adults who did nothing to stop it.
Laurie说了恶作剧发生的那天
Laurie said a substitute teacher and a mr. Ramsey
一个代课老师和Ramsey先生在场
Were there the day of the practical joke.
David Morrison肯定是嫌疑犯
David morrison had to be the sub.
Garcia  Ramsey先生现在在哪
Garcia, where's mr. Ramsey now?
Harold Ramsey  历史教师
Harold ramsey, history teacher.
他在Jefferson高中工作
Ll works at jefferson high.
好的  发过来联系电话和地址
All right, send contact numbers and addresses
Harold Ramsey和Ronald Underwood两个人的
For both harold ramsey and ronald underwood.
发送  已发送
Sent and sent.
多谢
Thanks.
谁
Hello?
喂  是Harold Ramsey么
Yes, is this harold ramsey?
是我
Yes, speaking.
你好  Ramsey先生  我是社会保障署的Alex Blake
Hello, mr. Ramsey. This is ssa alex blake.
我和FBI探员在一起
I'm with the fbi.
FBI
Fbi?
Ramsey先生
Mr. Ramsey?
啊
Aah!
Ramsey先生
Mr. Ramsey.
感觉怎么样
How does it feel?
你为什么要这么干
Why are you doing this?
我实在是希望他们都来这儿看到此景
I just wish they were all here to see it.
求你了
Please--
也许我们应该握握手然后忘掉这事
Maybe we should shake hands and forget about it.
那就是你想说的  对么
That's what you'd say, right?
你在说什么啊
What are you talking about?
Riley
Riley!
回班吧  你也是
Get to class. You, too!
各回各班
Everybody back to class.
表演结束了
Show's over!
啊
Aah!
你知道他们都对我们做了什么
You knew what they did to us.
而你却无动于衷
And you did nothing.
你想让我和他们握手言和
And you wanted me to shake their hands?
和他们握手言和
Shake their hands?!
你真的以为那样就能解决任何事
Did you actually think that would solve anything?
我们相信Underwood拥有
We believe underwood is in possession
一把被盗的警用Glock19枪
Of a stolen police issue glock 19.
我们分成3组
We'll split up into 3 groups,
我们要逐个房间排查
We'll go room to room,
然后我们回到主过道会面
and we'll all meet back in the main hallway.
因为我们回到了Underwood开始所有事的地方
Because we're back where it all started with underwood,
所以这儿也可能会是他的游戏终点
This is likely his endgame.
也就是说难以预料他何时会
Which means there's no telling how far
结束一切  所以诸位请保重
He'll go to play this thing out, so be safe.
啊
Uhh!
走啊
Go.
我让你走
I said go!
Ronald  求你了
Ronald, please.
我很惊讶你记得我的名字
I'm surprised you remember my name.
停手吧
Just stop this.
奥
Oh!
起来
Get up.
Get up!
走啊
Go.
动啊
Move!
Ronald Underwood  FBI  放下武器
Ronald underwood, fbi. Drop the weapon.
放他走吧  Ronald
Let him go, ronald.
他必须得知道这种感觉如何
He has to know how it felt.
我感觉他知道了
I think he does.
看看他
Look at him.
放他走吧
Let him go.
他本应该阻止的
He should have stopped it.
我知道你作这事儿的缘由  Ronald
I know why you're doing this, ronald.
发生在Riley身上的事并不是你的错
What happened to riley wasn't your fault.
没人阻止
Nobody stopped it.
没有人做任何努力
Nobody did anything.
你已经做了
You did.
你说对了
You're damn right.
他们应得的
And they got what they deserved.
但没人有必要丢命
But nobody else needs to die.
你得放下过去
You've got to leave the past in the past.
他是我唯一的朋友
He was the only friend I ever had.
我知道他是
I know he was.
但到此为止了  Ronald
But it's all over now, ronald.
伙计  没事儿  你没必要给我戴手铐
Hey, man, it's ok, you don't have to cuff me.
我说了不用拷着我
I said you don't have to cuff me!
放开我
Get off of me!
我说放开
I said get off!
太紧了  放了我
They're too tight! Get off of me!
我说放开
I said get off!
放开
停下  让我走
Stop! Get off of me!
拜托  放了我吧
Come on. Get off of me!
胳膊怎么样
How's the wing?
阵痛啊
Throbbing.
都还好吗？
You all good?
Jefferson是我高中时的对手
Jefferson was my rival high school.
那些日子弄个球  来点儿足球赛
Got dragged to a few football games here back in the day.
肯定会牵动回忆
It must bring back some memories.
是
Oh, yeah.
不好的记忆
Bad ones.
你兄弟怎么样了？
How's your brother doing?
脑震荡
Concussion.
但他醒了
But he's awake and...
他会没事的
He's gonna do fine.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
真好
Good.
想在这儿转转吗
Do you want a ride over there?
不了 我妈妈就是在这家医院去世的
Nah. It's the hospital where my mom died
danny也是
And my big brother danny, too.
所以
So...
不是很想回来这里
Not exactly raring to get back there.
头疼好点没？
How's the headache?
靠药好点
Well, the medicine's helping.
你很幸运
You got lucky.
没有后援你不该去的
You shouldn't have gone in without backup.
讽刺的是  你的铁头救了你
Ironic that your hard head is what saved you.
你真吓着我了
You really scared me, you know.
恭贺该一个接一个来了
I guess congratulations is in order.
为我们
Mm-hmm. For all of us.
我们是一起的
We did it together.
所以老爸是对的
So dad was right, then.
我讨厌那样
I hate that.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
听着
Listen, um...
我很抱歉
Listen, I'm really sorry, ok?
我真是一个混蛋  不值得你这样
I'm sorry for being an ass. You didn't deserve that.
不  不是
No, I didn't.
我不知道为什么你让我如此疯狂
And I don't know why you made me so mad.
因为我是你姐姐
Because I'm your sister.
平常兄妹都是这样抬扛
It's--it's normal for siblings to resent each other.
好吧  那算什么？
Ok, what is that?
你对我的定义？
What, is that your profile of me?
抬扛？
Resent?
听着  我不想和你争吵  alex
Look, I don't resent you, alex.
我想你
I miss you.
你肯定有妙法表示出来
You sure have a funny way of showing it.
你懂的  danny死后  你就走了
You know, after danny died, you just left.
妈妈随后
And then with mom, it's
就像  你走后时光停止
like you just stopped coming around altogether.
就像这会儿的你  我的老姐  你自由了
It's like here you are, my big sister, and you just bailed.
我不能呆这儿  Scott
I couldn't stay here, scott.
我知道  可你知道吗？相信我  我能做到
I know. You know what? Trust me, I get it, I figured it out.
但是有意思的是
But the funny thing is,
现在你是厉害的语言学家
Here you are this hot-shot linguist...
你可以保持沉默
And you can never say anything.
你从不打电话  不写信
You never call, you never write,
什么都不做
Nothing.
怎么了  你还好吗
What's wrong? You all right?
我的胳膊  中枪了
Oh, yeah. It's just my arm. I got shot.
什么  看  就是这里
Ok, what? See, right there.
的确如我所说
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
没什么
It's nothing.
我很好
I'm fine.
真的 爸爸知道吗
Oh, really? Does dad know?
不知道
No.
当然不  他为什么要知道
Of course not. Why would he?
但你是对的
But you're right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
保持联系让我感觉很不好
I'm bad about being in touch.
而回家
And coming home,
这对我来说很困难
It's really hard for me.
我见到你就想起danny
I see you and I think of danny.
爸爸
I see dad and...
还有妈妈
I think of mom.
但我正在为此努力
But I'll work on it.
我保证
I promise.
我也想你
And I miss you, too.
哈喽
Hello?
哦
Oh...
你们迟到了
You're late.
只是
Like...
五分钟而已
What-- 5 minutes.
那你也是迟到了
You're still late.
瓜怎样 警察
How's the melon? Hey, pop.
恩  还不错  很好
It's, uh, it's all right. It's fine.
你俩和好了  是吗
Ahh, you two made up, didn't you?
我知道了  你们小时候就经常这样
Yeah, I figured-- heh heh--been doing that since you were kids.
像猫狗一样打架  但十分钟后就忘了
Fight like cats and dogs, then forget about it 10 minutes later.
常常让你们母亲抓狂
Used to drive your mother crazy.
然后她再向我发飙
Then she'd drive me crazy.
警察  你知道她中枪了吗？
Hey, pop, you know she got shot?
好极了
Oh, that's great.
好吧
Well...
没错  我听说了
Yeah, I heard.
你听说了？
You heard?
Miller先生？
Mr. Miller?
再来点冰块
We need more ice.
自便  怎么了
Hey, what's up? Help yourself.
你一定是Scott  我是Penelope
You must be scott. I'm penelope.
嗨
Hi.
你在这儿干嘛？
What are you doing here?
我邀请的他们
I invited them.
是
Yeah.
只是俩个半小时的航程
It's only a 2 1/2 hour flight.
当我听说堪萨斯城烧烤  我就飞奔而来了
When I hear kansas city barbecue I come a-runnin',
相对他们  我是一个素食主义者
For the sides and the fixin's. I'm a vegetarian.
你什么意思  他们
What do you mean, them?
你们都在这儿啊
Oh, you're all here.
我的世界发生碰撞了啊
My worlds are colliding.
你爸爸答应了要烤排骨
And your dad promised ribs.
你老爸的烤肉可真不是盖的
And your pops is no joke on this grill.
全家人聚齐了才能庆祝
Can't celebrate unless the whole family's here.
我没意见
I can't argue with that.
谁需要冰的
And who needs a cold one?
就算我有意见也别介意  干杯
Don't mind if I do. Cheers.
为了Blake  为Blake干杯
To blake. To blake.
一人势单力薄
"Alone we can do so little.
众人齐力断金
Together we can do so much."
Helen keller
Helen keller.